Sibdou Ibrahim Issifu

Companies Companies Comp

in LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/sibdou-issifu

• Home: Tarkwa, (Ghana)

ABOUT ME

I am a dedicated Computer Science and Engineering student with over four years of extensive experience in computer programming and a keen interest in front-end development. I am passionate about utilizing computer technology to solve societal problems and drive innovation in Africa, with a focus on ensuring the security of software applications developed.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelance Front-End Developer (Remote)

Pentagram Design Company [02/2024 – 05/2024]

City: San Francisco | Country: United States

- Developed responsive web designs using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and ReactJS to create engaging and interactive user experiences.
- Customized WordPress themes and plugins to meet client requirements and industry best practices for security, performance, and scalability.

Software Developer Intern

Kologsoft Software Solutions [10/2023 - 12/2023]

City: Bolgatanga | Country: Ghana

- Developed 2 responsive web interfaces using HTML, Bootstrap, and JavaScript.
- Tested and developed front-end for mobile applications using Flutter.
- Developed and maintained server-side logic, APIs, and databases for web applications using PHP.

IoT Tutor

UMaT Aenics Robotics Club [07/2023 - Current]

- Leading hands-on tutorials where students gain practical experience in configuring IoT devices and programming microcontrollers (e.g., Arduino, Raspberry Pi, NodeMCU)
- Mentoring students in the development of IoT projects, ranging from smart home automation systems to environmental monitoring solutions.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

BSc. Computer Science and Engineering

University of Mines and Technology [01/2022 - Current]

City: Tarkwa | Country: Ghana

Projects:

• Smart Water Monitoring Device with Blynk. The device monitors real-time water level and water quality(pH, turbidity and TDS) for domesticated water in mining areas.

- Remote-controlled Camera Robot.
- Web Application for the management of a pharmaceutical company's database.

Google Cybersecurity Professional Certificate

Coursera [07/2023 - 04/2024]

DIGITAL SKILLS

IoT Programming / Web Design & Web development / Cybersecurity tools / Programming (Java, C++, Python)

Soft Skills

Problem-solving / Adaptability / Communication (Oral and Written) / Creativity and Attention to Detail.